Guide to The Parasite Archive MSS.333
Fales Library and Special Collections
Parasite Archive
1966-1999
1991-1999
Fales Library and Special Collections
Parasite
Kinmont, Ben
MSS.333
5.5 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons, 2 oversize boxes, 1 manuscript box
Parasite was an artist-run organization, primarily active between the years 1997 to 1998, that was committed to supporting, documenting, and presenting project-based artwork. The Archive includes administrative records, articles, books, correspondence, ephemera, photography, promotional materials, objects, and audiovisual elements.
Historical Note
Parasite was an artist-run organization that was committed to supporting, documenting, and presenting project-based artwork. Primarily active between the years 1997 - 1998, Parasite aimed to establish a discursive context for project work and related issues. As a secondary (or para) site for projects undertaken at other locations, Parasite aspired to develop this discursive context by a variety of activities undertaken from within "host" organizations. Through these activities, Parasite sought to challenge existing modes of the presentation and distribution of art, and to develop new modes of individual and organizational participation in artists' projects.
Among Parasite's activities were the temporary occupation of existing organizations for the purpose of presenting projects in various stages of development. Presentations, symposia, discussion groups, and other public programs concentrated on issues taken up by particular artists as well as concerns relevant to the field, such as artistic autonomy, censorship, and sponsorship. In addition, Parasite continuously updated the "Parasite Document Collection," which developed into an aquisition of contemporary and historical documents relating to project-based activity, including records of completed projects and, where possible, proposals, contracts, and correspondence.
-- Adapted from The Parasite Mission Statement, 1997 (The Parasite Archive; MSS 333; Box 4; Folder 96; Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University Libraries).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers.
Arrangement
Within each series, materials are arranged alphabetically or chronologically where noted.
Series I: Parasite Document Collection preserves a collection of contemporary and historical documents relating to project-based activity. Materials on particular artists and works include documentation of completed projects and, where possible, proposals, contracts, correspondence, and ephemera. These materials are arranged alphabetically by artist, item title, or subject.
Series II: Services: A Working - Group Exhibition includes materials pertaining to Andrea Fraser's project of the same title. These materials are arranged alphabetically by artist, item title, or subject.
Series III: Administrative contains Parasite management records. These materials are arranged alphabetically then chronologically. Subseries A: Parasite Files preserves correspondence between artists and institutions, meeting minutes, and promotional material. These materials are arranged alphabetically, then chronologically.
Subseries B: Ben Kinmont Files consists of records preserved by Parasite treasurer Ben Kinmont. These materials are arranged chronologically.
Series IV: Video recordings includes project recordings from the Parasite Document Collection in addition to Helmet Draxler and Andrea Fraser's "Services." These materials are arranged chronologically. Access Copies may not be available for consultation at this time, please ask a Fales archivist.
Series V: Audio recordings contains recordings of Parasite presentations, symposia, discussion groups, and other public programs of interest. These materials are arranged chronologically. Access Copies may not be available for consultation at this time, please ask a Fales archivist.
Subseries VI: Data Storage preserves computer files stored on disk. This element may not be available for consultation, please ask a Fales archivist.
Provenance
The Parasite Archive was donated to the Fales Library in 2011 by members of the collective. The bulk of the collection (the Parasite Document Collection, as well as Services Files and some administrative files) had been stored in a filing cabinet created by Parasite as a public resource. The filing cabinet was transferred to Fales from the Shedhalle in Zurich, Switzerland, where it had been shipped as part of a project in the late 1990s. The remainder of the collection was donated directly from Ben Kinmont, who was the group's treasurer.
Scope and Content
The Parasite Archive includes administrative records, articles, correspondence, ephemera, photography, promotional materials, objects, and audiovisual elements. The bulk of the collection is from the Parasite Document Collection, which was a resource of contemporary and historical documents relating to project-based activity, created by the collective during their active years, and is supplemented by administrative records saved by the Collective, and by their treasurer Ben Kinmont.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Public art spaces.; Art -- Exhibitions.; Art criticism.; Art -- Collectors and collecting.; Art patronage.; Alternative spaces (Arts facilities).; Art |x Management |z United States; Art -- Censorship -- United States.; Art galleries (institutions); Art and society.; Art and state.; Politics in art.; Conceptual art.; Ault, Julie; Sholette, Gregory; Zeyfang, Florian; Müller, Christian Philipp; Koenig, Janet; LeWitt, Sol, 1928-2007; Marclay, Christian; Kafehsy, Sylvia; Karamustafa, Gülsün; Fraser, Andrea; Green, Renée; Dion, Mark, 1961-; Fend, Peter; Cottingham, Laura; Biemann, Ursula; Bauer, Ute Meta; Beck, Martin; Barry, Judith; Kinmont, Ben; Kinmont, Ben
- Series I: Parasite Document Collection
  Scope and Content
  Series I: Parasite Document Collection preserves a collection of contemporary and historical documents relating to project-based activity created by the collective as a public resource. Materials on particular artists and works include documentation of completed projects and, where possible, proposals, contracts, correspondence, and ephemera. These materials are arranged alphabetically by artist, item title, or subject.
  - Ault, Julie, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Barry, Judith, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bauer, Ute Meta, [c1993] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Beck, Martin, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biemann, Ursula, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Botschaft / Berlin, 1984, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - [Catalogs, Flyers], various (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cottingham, Laura, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cultural Economies: Histories from the Alternative Arts Movement, NYC Organized by Julie Ault, The Drawing Center, February 24 - April 6, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Culture in Action by Mary Jane Jacob, Michael Brenson, and Eva M. Olson, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dion, Mark [1 of 2], 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dion, Mark [2 of 2], 1990 - 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Documents: Volume 1, Number 1/2, Fall / Winter 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Documents: Numbers 4/5 - 6, 1994 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Documents: Numbers 7 - 10, 1996 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Eichhon, Maria: "What is the origin of a city?", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Electronic Arts Intermix: Video edited by Lori Zippay, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - environ 27 ans (peut-être un peu plus): pratiques artistiques et féminismes [2 copies], February - March 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fend, Peter, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fraser, Andrea: Eine Gesellschaft des Geschmacks, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Fraser, Andrea [1 of 2], 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fraser, Andrea [2 of 2], 1991 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Games Fights Collaborations: Das Spiel con Grenze und Überschreitung, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Green, Renée, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hors Sol: Reflexionen zur Ausstellungspraxis Réflexions sur la pratique de l'exposition - Sous-Sol Genève, Shedhalle Zurich, October 1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - In Public: Seattle 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Inventory: Volume 2, Number 2, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Kafehsy, Sylvia, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Karamustafa, Gülsün, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Kinmont, Ben, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Kinmont, Ben: Vietnam War Ads; or, your bibliography is our sculpture [Two T-Shirts], 1998 (Box 2)
  - Kültür: ein Gender-Projekt aus Istanbul - Shedhalle Zürich, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Kunstraum der Univerität Lüneburg: Dokumentation 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Kwon, Miwon: "One Place After Another: Notes on Site Specificity", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - LeWitt, Sol, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Marclay, Christian [1 of 2], 1993 - 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Marclay, Christian [2 of 2], 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mega-Shows, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Müller, Christian Philipp, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - October 80, Spring 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "On taking a normal situation and retranslating it into overlapping and multiple readings of conditions past and present" - Antwepen 93, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Platzwechsel: Ursula Biemann, Tom Burr, Mark Dion, Christian Philipp Müller - Kunsthalle Zürich [2 copies], June - July 1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - REPO History Collective [1 of 2], 1993 - 1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    General
    These materials were originally housed with oversized materials that have been relocated. Please see OVERSIZE Series I: Parasite Document Collection to review the remainder of this file.
  - Skulptur Projekte in Münster 1997 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Shedhalle: Programs, 1994 - 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Shedhalle Zurich [1 of 3], 1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sholette, Greg + Koenig, Janet, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Simon, Jason, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Springer - Band 3, Booklet 3, October - November 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Thames and Hudson Rivers Project", 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Wiley, Daniel, [c1997] (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Zeyfang, Florian, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - zingmagazine: a curatorial crossing, Winter 1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Series II: Services: A Working-Group Exhibition
  Series II: Services: A Working - Group Exhibition includes materials pertaining to Andrea Fraser's project of the same title. These materials are arranged alphabetically by artist, item title, or subject.
  - "112 Green Street", undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Angry Arts Against the War in Vietnam", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "Art Workers Coalition Documents, 1969" (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "Art Workers Coalition Documents, 1970 - 1971" (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Art Workers Coalition, 'New American Painting and Sculpture: The First Generation' ", June 13, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Art Workers Coalition Opening Hearing", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Artists Meeting for Cultural Change", 1975 - 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "The Artist's Reserved Rights Transfer and Sale Agreement", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Asher, Michael, 1970 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Backstage: Kunstverein in Hamburg", September - October 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Barry, Judith: "Designed Aesthetic: Exhibition Design and the Independent Group", [c1988] (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Barry, Judith: "FRAC du Corse", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Barry, Judith: "Ken Saylor Architecture Contracts", 1988 - 1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Barry, Judith: "Ken Saylor Exhibition Design Materials", 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Barry, Judith: "Typical Commercial Contract", 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bauer, Ute Meta: "Informationsdienst", October 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bauer, Ute Meta: "Künstlerhaus Stuttgart", 1990 - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bauer, Ute Meta: "La Exposicion Ideal", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bischoff, Ulrich, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Blazwick, Iwona: "Antwerp 93", 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Blazwick, Iwona: "Gordon Matta-Clark", 1974 -1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bochner, Mel, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Broodthaers, Marcel, 1969 - 1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Buren, Daniel, 1967 - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Büro, Bert: "Asta und Studenten der Kunstacademie Düsseldorf", [1993] (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Büro, Bert: "Wohlfahrtsausschuss Köln", [1993] (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cahan, Susan: "Homemade TV, Branda Miller, The New Museum of Contemporary Art", 1990 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cahan, Susan: "Laurie Parsons Project for Spatial Drive, New Museum of Contemporary Art", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Cahan, Susan: "Resource Room with Julie Ault, New Museum of Contemporary Art", 1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Clegg & Guttman: "Die offene Bibliothek (The Open Library), Hamburg", 1993 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Commodity and Contradiction, or, Contradiction as Commodity" by Carl Andre and Jeremy Gilbert-Rolfe, Summer 1976 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Conde & Beveridge: "(Scan PAD/Lucy Lippard Archive, MOMA)", 1988 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "The Desire of the Museum," Whitney Downtown, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Dillemuth, Stephan: "Friesenwall 120", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Dillemuth, Stephan: "Internets 94", 1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dion, Mark: "Chicago Urban Art Ecology Group", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dion, Mark: "Sculpture Chicago" [1 of 2], 1992 - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    These materials were originally housed with oversized materials that have been relocated. Please see OVERSIZE Series II: Services: A Working Group Exhibition to review the remainder of this file.
  - "Docklands Community Poster Project", undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - "Dokumentation", October 1993 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Draxler, Helmut: "Working Group Presentation", undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Fashion Moda: "Documenta 7", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Fraser, Andrea: "Aren't They Lovely?" University Art Museum, Berkeley, CA, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Fraser, Andrea: "Damaged Goods: Desire and the Economy of the Object," New Museum of Contemporary Art, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Fraser, Andrea: "Preliminary Prospectuses, Project Office Outline", 1993 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Fraser, Andrea: "Recorded Tour," Whitney Biennial Exhibition, 1992 - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Fraser, Andrea: "What's Intangible, Transitory, Mediating, Participatory, and Rendered in the Public Sphere?", [c1993] (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Fraser, Andrea: "Wiener Secession Exhibition", 1993 - 1994 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - "Goods, Services and the Future of Work" by Jonathan I. Gershuny, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Graham, Dan, 1966 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Green, Renée: "Negotiations in the Contract Zone," The Drawing Center, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Group Material, 1980 - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Guerilla Girls, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Haacke, Hans, various (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - "Herstory - A Documentary", 1970 -1971 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Huebler, Douglas, 1968 - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - "Information," Museum of Modern Art, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - "Installation Photographs," Kunstraum det Universität Lüneburg, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "International Board of Artists" (PAD Archive / Lippard, MOMA), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Judd, Donald: "Una stanza per Panza", undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Knight, John, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - "Kontext Kunst," Neue Galerie, Graz, Austria, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Kunstraum der Universität Lüneburg - Press, January 1994 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Lawler, Louise, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - LeWitt, Sol, 1967 - 1968 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - "Misc. Art Actions", 1968 - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - "Misc. Artists Organizations", 1974 - 1982 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - "Misc. Letters of Invitation + Requests for Project Submission, Misc. Exhibitions", 1991 - 1994 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Müller, Christian Philipp, 1988 - 1989 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Museum für Angewandte Kunst Installation Contract, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Museum in Progress, Vienna, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - "Museum: A Project of Living Artists" (PAD Archive, MOMA), undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - "Pasta MOMA, Unionization Drive", 1971 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - "People's Art Gang Communique #7", May Day, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - "The Professional - Managerial Class" by Barbara & John Ehrenreich, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Project Artist Questionnaires, January 2, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Public Figure Disclosure Form, Artist Questionnaire of American Fine Arts Company, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Rahmann, Fritz, undated, 1980 - 1986 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - "RE: Placement," LACE (Los Angeles Contemporary Exhibitions), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Research Records, Museum of Modern Art, January 7, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Rosler, Martha, 1978, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Scher, Julia, 1990, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Smithson, Robert: "Towards the Development of an Air Terminal Site", 1966 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - The Times Square Summer Art Spectacular - Media Alert, June 1980 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - [Titles for Installation], undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Ukele, Mierle Laderman, 1969, 1982, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - UNITE - Exhibition Art Architecture Design, Firminy, France, 1991 - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - The Waitresses, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Wilson, Ian: "That Which is Both Known and Unknown", March 18 [no year] (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Women Artists in Revolution, 1970 - 1971 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - "Working - Group Discussions" Conference Document for October 80, Spring 1997 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Working - Group Programs and Press, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 85)
- Series III: Administrative
  Series III: Administrative contains Parasite management records. These materials are arranged alphabetically then chronologically.
  Subseries A: Parasite Files preserves correspondence between artists and institutions, meeting minutes, and promotional material. These materials are arranged alphabetically, then chronologically.
  Subseries B: Ben Kinmont Files consists of records saved by Parasite treasurer Ben Kinmont. These materials are arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries A: Parasite Files
    - [Correspondence 1], November - December 1997 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - [Correspondence 2], January - February 1998 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - [Correspondence 3], March - April 1998 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - [Correspondence 4], May - September 1998 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - [Meeting Minutes], 1997 - 1998 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Parasite at The Clocktower, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Parasite at The Drawing Center, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Parasite at The Swiss Institute, November 18, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Parasite Funding Committee: Proposal for Parasite Subscription, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Parasite Mailing List, 1/25/98 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Parasite Mission Statement, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Parasite Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - "Parasite - Swiss Inst. Swap" [Meeting Minutes], 1997 - 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Parasite Web Site - May Update", May 24, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Ben Kinmont Files
    - [July 1997] (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - [August 1997] (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - [September 1997] (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - [September 1997: Receipts] (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - [October 1997], Ocotber 1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - [November 1997] (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - [December 1997] (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Parasite '98 Invoices", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - [January 1998] (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - [February 1998] (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - [March 1998] (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - [April 1998] (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - [May 1998] (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - [June 1998] (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Video recordings
  Series IV: Video includes project recordings from the Parasite Document Collection in addition to Helmet Draxler and Andrea Fraser's "Services." These materials are arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access copies for some materials are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
  - "Some Installations" by Judith Barry, 1985 - 1996; ID: 333.0001 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0001, Box Shared Fales 133, Dvd 333.0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Original format: VHS
    Duration: 39 minutes.
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Access DVD available.
  - "Moving a Border by Moving a River & OECD Trailer" by Peter Fend / OECD, 1988; ID: 333.0002 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0002, Box Shared Fales 133, Dvd 333.0002)
    Duration: 55 minutes.
  - "Services: Sektion 1", January 1994; ID: 333.0003 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0003, Box Shared Fales 133, Dvd 333.0003)
    Duration: 64 minutes.
  - "Services: Sektion 2", January 1994; ID: 333.0004 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0004, Box Shared Fales 133, Dvd 333.0004)
    Duration: 179 minutes.
  - "Services: Sektion 3", January 1994; ID: 333.0005 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0005, Box Shared Fales 133, Dvd 333.0005)
    Duration: 133 minutes.
  - "Services: Sektion 4", January 1994; ID: 333.0006 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0006, Box Shared Fales 132, Dvd 333.0006)
    Duration: 130 minutes.
  - "Services: Sektion 5", January 1994; ID: 333.0007 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0007, Box Shared Fales 132, Dvd 333.0007)
    Duration: 164 minutes.
  - "Services: Sektion 6", January 1994; ID: 333.0008 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0008, Box Shared Fales 132, Dvd 333.0008)
    Duration: 99 minutes.
  - "Dissociation I" by Mike Ballou & Adam Simon, 1997; ID: 333.0009 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0009, Box Shared Fales 132, Dvd 333.0009)
    Duration: 42 minutes.
  - "Corita Kent On Teaching & Celebration - Target City Hall", undated; ID: 333.0010 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0010, Box Shared Fales 132, Dvd 333.0010)
    Duration: 63 minutes.
- Series V: Audio recordings
  Series V: Audio contains recordings of Parasite presentations, symposia, discussion groups, and other public programs of interest. These materials are arranged chronologically.
  - "An Introduction to the 1993 Biennial Exhibition of the Whitney Museum of American Art" by Andrea Fraser, ID: 333.0029 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0029)
    Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
    Duration: 45 minutes
    Original format: Audiocassette
    This audio element was originally found with corresponding documentation preserved in Series II: Services - A Working - Group Exhibition: "Fraser, Andrea: Recorded Tour, Whitney Biennial Exhibition."
  - "Services", 1994; ID: 333.0011 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0011)
  - "CPM Documenta X Tape 1", January 7, 1998; ID: 333.0012 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0012)
  - "CPM Documenta X Tape 2", January 7,1998; ID: 333.0013 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0013)
  - "Parasite Discussion with Mel Bochner, Tape 1", February 27, 1998; ID: 333.0014 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0014, Case 333.0014)
    Currently available.
    Audiocassette access copy available.
    Original Format: Audiocassette
  - "Parasite Discussion with Mel Bochner, Tape 2", February 27, 1998; ID: 333.0015 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0015, Case 333.0015)
  - "REPO History at Parasite", March 24, 1998; ID: 333.0016 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0016)
  - "Parasite Meeting on Site-Specificity, etc.", June 3, 1998; ID: 333.0017 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0017, Case 333.0017)
  - "Tape #1 - Parasite Sur L'Herbe or, Slippages", July 4, 1998; ID: 333.0018 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0018)
  - "#2 - Prin Tempe du Parasite", July 4, 1998; ID: 333.0019 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0019)
  - "#3 - Parasite (American Canvas con't)", July 4, 1998; ID: 333.0020 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0020)
  - "#4 - Parasite (American Canvas con't)", July 4, 1998; ID: 333.0021 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0021)
  - "Parasite #5", July 4, 1998; ID: 333.0022 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0022)
  - "PS, Day 2, Tape 3", 1998; ID: 333.0023 (Box 6, Media ID: 333.0023)